two times throughout my counseling
在我的咨询过程中两次
ministry throughout the years doing
多年来一直在做事工
marriage counseling I've had people say
婚姻咨询我曾经有人说过
almost this exact same thing to me if
对我来说几乎完全相同的事情
God designed marriage he must be cruel
上帝设计婚姻他必须是残忍的
and that really reflects what's going on
这真的反映了正在发生的事情
in our culture right for our culture to
在我们的文化中，对我们的文化来说
think that marriage is just nasty
认为婚姻只是令人讨厌
it is absolutely no secret that marriage
婚姻绝对不是秘密
is in a demise in the United States
是在美国去世
right now and I've prayed often through
现在 ，我已经通过经常祈祷
the years that the Lord would restore a
主要恢复的年代
marriage culture in the United States we
我们在美国的婚姻文化
certainly don't live in a marriage
当然不要生活在婚姻中
culture where marriage is viewed
观看婚姻的文化
positively in the United States our
积极地在美国我们
topic right now is the purposes of
现在的主题是目的
marriage and what I say to people when
婚姻和我对人们说的话
they give me that line that if God
他们给了我那条如果上帝的话
designed marriage he must be cruel is
设计婚姻他必须是残忍的
it's not a problem with the design it's
它不是与它的设计有问题
the way we're using the tool and let me
我们使用该工具的方式让我
give you an illustration there's nothing
给你一个例子没什么
wrong with God's design in fact I think
事实上，我认为上帝的设计是错误的
God's ways work the way the architect
上帝的方式与建筑师一样
designed it it works great if we follow
设计它如果我们遵循它是很有效的
his blueprints but we're trying to build
他的蓝图，但我们正在努力建立
the house the wrong way we're trying to
房子是我们想要的错误方式
ignore his blueprints and turn marriage
忽视他的蓝图，转变婚姻
into things that God never intended and
成的事情，上帝从来没有打算和
therefore that's how abuse is happening
因此，虐待是如何发生的
in marriage here's an illustration for
在婚姻这里的一个例证
you I had a great job when I was in high
我在高中的时候表现得很好
school I just absolutely loved it
学校我非常喜欢它
because I like being outdoors and a man
因为我喜欢在户外和男人
who owned the largest nursery on the
谁拥有的最大的苗圃
East Coast
东海岸
hired me to be his private gardener and
雇我成为他的私人园丁
so I got to work outside during the
所以我就在外面 工作
summer I worked for him 60 hours a week
夏天我每周工作60个小时
and I got the mow as Long's and do all
我把割草作为Long's并做了所有
the landscaping and weed
美化和杂草
weed and weed and weed and one time he
杂草，杂草和杂草，有一次他
had me developing a new garden area for
让我开发一个新的花园区
him and in this garden area in the soil
他和在土壤中的这个花园区域
there were lots of rocks so we had a big
有很多岩石，所以我们有一个大的
sieve setup and I would throw the dirt
筛子设置，我会扔污垢
on the sieve the rocks would come
在筛子上岩石会来
tumbling down and the good dirt would go
倒下来，好的污垢会消失
through the sieve and we were using the
通过筛子， 我们正在使用
good dirt
好污垢
to build this new beautiful flower
建造这朵新的美丽花朵
garden area in a little wooded area well
在一个小树林面积的花园区以及
there were lot since it was a wooded
因为它是树木繁茂的，所以有很多
area there were lots of roots of trees
那里有很多树根
in that area and I got tired of putting
在那个地区，我厌倦了推杆
down the rake and picking up the shovel
沿着耙子拿起铲子
or the pick to get rid of all the roots
或者选择摆脱所有根源
that were in that area he wanted me to
那个地方他想要我
get rid of surface roots so that we
摆脱表面的根源让我们
could put then about a six inch or 8
然后可以放大约6英寸或8英寸
inch layer of really good soil so I was
英寸层真的很好土我所以
using the stone rake to dig at roots and
用石耙在根部挖掘
this was on a Saturday and he wasn't
这是在星期六而他不是
down at his office on a Saturday and he
星期六在他的办公室和他
was watching from the house and I didn't
从房子里看，我却没有
realize that so I'm taking his rake and
意识到所以我正在拿他的佣金和
I'm just pounding away at the ground
我只是在地上挣扎着
with his rake and pulling at the roots
用他的耙子和拉根
with his rake now normally he's a very
现在通常他的耙子非常好
nice man only two times in the two years
这两年好男人只有两次
that I worked for him do I remember him
我为他工作的我是否记得他
getting angry and this was one of the
生气，这是其中之一
times he came storming out of the house
有一次他冲出房子
and he was a little guy and he looked up
他是一个小家伙，他抬起头来
at me and he started reading me the riot
在我和他开始读我的骚乱
act about that rake was not designed to
关于那个耙子的行为不是为了设计的
do what you're making it do you're gonna
你正在做什么它做你会
break my rake use the appropriate tool
打破我的佣金使用适当的工具
now through the years as I've thought
正如我所想的那样
about this statement if God designed
关于上帝设计的这个陈述
marriage he must be cruel
结婚他一定很残忍
I've thought people are using the tool
我以为人们都在使用这个工具
in the wrong way it's nothing there's
以错误的方式，它什么都没有
nothing wrong with the design there's
设计没有任何问题
nothing wrong with the blueprint it's
它的蓝图没有错
that our culture is abusing marriage so
我们的文化如此滥用婚姻
let's see if we can get back to the
让我们看看我们是否可以回到
blueprint this morning and think about
今天早上的蓝图和思考
what did God design
上帝设计了什么
marriage to be and the emphasis for me
婚姻和我的重点
is gonna be since I work with college
因为我和大学一起工作会是这样的
students and I'm really interested in it
学生和我在它真正感兴趣
helping people make a wise choice of a
帮助人们作出的一个明智的选择
marriage partner and get ready for
婚姻伴侣并为此做好准备
marriage in the right way what I'm gonna
我正在以正确的方式结婚
do as we go through this is try to focus
我们经历这一点是试着集中精力
all the applications on how do we help
关于我们如何提供帮助的所有申请
young people make a wise choice of a
年轻人做出明智的选择
marriage partner what kind of questions
婚姻伴侣有什么样的问题
should they be asking because that's a
他们应该问，因为这是一个
really big deal in our culture right now
现在我们的文化真的很重要
is how do you make a wise choice of a
你是如何做出明智选择的？
marriage partner so in your notes you
婚姻伴侣所以在你的笔记你
have under the introduction to build
有建设的介绍
their marriage upon a biblical basis a
他们在圣经的基础上结婚了
couple must be committed to fulfill
夫妇必须致力于履行
God's purposes for marriage I'm not
上帝的婚姻目的我不是
going to go through all those common
要经历所有这些共同点
reasons why people get married you could
人们结婚的原因你可以
probably add all kinds of things to that
可能会添加各种各样的东西
list of why people get married I just
为什么人们结婚的清单我就是
want to comment on one thing and it's
想评论一件事，而且是
the soulmate idea in our culture and let
我们文化中的灵魂伴侣的想法让我们
me give you some cautions about the idea
我给你一些关于这个想法的警告
of the soulmate think about what we're
灵魂伴侣思考我们是什么
saying about a soulmate I have to find
谈到我必须找到的灵魂伴侣
my soulmate it's kind of like an of
我的灵魂伴侣有点像
Green Gables I've got to find my kindred
Green Gables我必须找到我的亲戚
spirit and there's this one right person
精神，这是一个合适的人
out there in the world and we're just
在外面的世界和我们只是
going to kind of the chemistry's gonna
将一种化学 的要的
be right and we're gonna blend together
是对的，我们要融合在一起
and I'm gonna find my perfect soul mate
我会找到我完美的灵魂伴侣
I follow marriage trends I'm kind of
我跟随婚姻趋势，我有点儿
geeky about marriage trends and there's
对于婚姻趋势而言，这是令人讨厌的
an annual report I may have told you
我可能告诉过你的年度报告
about it last time that comes out called
关于它最后一次出来叫出来
the state of our unions report it used
我们工会的状态报告使用了它
to be published by Rutgers University
由罗格斯大学出版
it's now published by the archrival
它现在由竞争对手发布
of Virginia Tech University the
美国弗吉尼亚理工大学的
University of Virginia and just had to
弗吉尼亚大学刚刚不得不
get a little bit of Hokies humor in
得到一点Hokies的幽默
there sorry for the East Coast humor and
抱歉东海岸的幽默和
it's called the National Marriage
它被称为全国婚姻
project and every year they put out a
项目，每年他们推出一个
state of our unions report it's a
我们的工会状态报告它是一个
secular report on what has happened in
世俗报道发生了什么事
marriage trends in the United States in
美国的婚姻趋势
the last year it's worth reading it's
去年它值得一读
free
自由
and it comes out the end of June
它出现在六月底
beginning of July
七月初
every year one year 2005 they had this
每年一年，2005年他们都有这个
exact statement and I thought this was
确切的说法，我认为这是
so interesting especially related to
如此有趣特别是有关
what I do is a biblical counsellor they
我所做的是他们的圣经辅导员
said Americans are looking for a
说美国人正在寻找一个
spiritual eyes Union of souls this is
属灵的眼睛这是灵魂联盟
not believers putting this out out this
不信把这个搞出来这个
is a secular report Americans are
是美国人的世俗报道
looking for a spiritual eyes Union of
寻找灵性的眼睛联盟
souls a soul mate now let's just think
灵魂是一个灵魂伴侣现在让我们想一想
about this for a minute and then think
这个一分钟，然后想
about what did God really design I'm
关于上帝真正设计的是什么
looking for somebody in my life a
寻找生命中的某个人
spiritual eyes Union of souls a soul
精神眼睛灵魂联盟灵魂
mate who will be my rock my perfect need
我的完美需要将是我的摇滚伴侣
meter well think what you're doing when
米很好想想你在做什么
you when you do that you're putting a
当你这么做的时候， 你就是这么做的
person on a pedestal you're putting a
你正在放一个基座的人
Genesis 3 person on a pedestal and they
创世纪3人在一个基座和他们
can never live up to all those
永远不会辜负所有这些
expectations that we're placing on them
我们对他们的期望
I need my wife but let me try to
我需要我的妻子，但让我尝试
illustrate it for you I need my wife as
为你说明我需要我的妻子
a rock in my life but I need the Lord as
我生命中的一块石头， 但我需要主
the rock in my life if I try to make
如果我试图制作，我生命中的摇滚
Rose the rock in my life I am putting
在我的生活 玫瑰岩 我把
her on a pedestal and she can never live
她在一个基座上，她永远不会活下去
up to all of those expectations I
达到所有这些期望我
believe that's a huge danger that's
相信这是一个巨大的危险， 这是
going on in the United States right now
现在在美国继续
of people looking for the perfect need
寻找完美需求的人
meter the person who is going to be
计算将要成为的人
their perfect soul mate it really helps
他们完美的灵魂伴侣真的很有帮助
young people go a long way toward
年轻人走了很长的路
choosing a spouse when they realize
当他们意识到选择配偶时
every other human you're looking at is
你正在看的每一个人都是
living with a Genesis 3 hangover
和Genesis 3宿醉一起生活
everybody's got a Genesis 3 hangover
每个人都有一个Genesis 3宿醉
I've been infected by it you've been
我已经被你感染了
infected by it there is no such thing as
通过它感染有没有这样的东西
a perfect soul mate it just can't happen
一个完美的灵魂伴侣，它是不可能发生的
in the world that we're living in now
在我们现在生活的世界里
let's go into biblical purposes and I
让我们进入圣经的目的和我
have six different things here they're
他们有六种不同的东西
all seized and then I want to try to
所有抓住然后我想尝试
give you some
给你一些
applications of these in conclusion so
这些应用总结如此
purpose number one and we're mainly
目的是第一，我们主要是
going to be in Genesis 1 in Genesis 2 so
要在创世纪1在成因2，从而
you can open up your Bibles to Genesis 1
你可以把你的圣经打开到创世纪1
Genesis 2 and what I'd like to do to
创世纪2和我想做的事情
begin with is I'm gonna read these
开始是我会读这些
crucial verses I'm not going to be
关键经文我不会
addressing the issue of home this talk
解决家庭这个问题的问题
could go all kinds of different
可以各种各样的
directions we could be talking about
我们可以谈论的方向
cohabitation we could be talking about
我们可以谈论同居
homosexuality there's all kinds of
同性恋有各种各样的
different directions this talk could go
这个谈话可能会有不同的方向
because of what's going on in marriage
因为 婚姻 中发生的事情
in the United States but we're just
在美国，但我们只是
gonna stay general about God's general
要保持关于上帝将军的一般性
purposes for marriage but let me make
婚姻的目的，但让我做
this one statement even though about
这个声明即使是关于
homosexuality even though this
同性恋即使这样
homosexuality is not mentioned in
没有提到同性恋
Genesis 1 and 2 Genesis 2 is absolutely
创世纪1和2创世记2绝对是
the most important passage in the Bible
圣经中最重要的一段
addressing the issue of homosexuality
解决同性恋问题
and here's why because Genesis 2 tells
这就是为什么因为Genesis 2说的
us God's purposes for marriage and I
我们上帝的婚姻和我的目的
know you've heard it before but it's
知道你以前听过它但是它
Adam and Eve and not Adam and Steve
亚当和夏娃，而不是亚当和史蒂夫
that's Genesis 2 makes it very clear
那个创世记2章非常清楚
what God's original intentions were for
上帝的初衷是什么
marriage so I believe even though
婚姻，所以我相信即使
homosexuality isn't even mentioned in
甚至没有提到同性恋
Genesis 2 it is laying the foundation
创世纪2 正在奠定基础
Genesis 1 and 2 are telling us what did
创世纪1和2告诉我们做了什么
the grand designer what did the grand
伟大的设计师是什么盛大的
engineer the universe designed for
工程师设计的宇宙
marriage Genesis 1 and to make it very
结婚创世纪1并使它成为非常
clear now here's what I'm gonna do I'm
现在清楚这就是我要做的事情
gonna read verses 26 to 28 and then I'm
要读26到28节， 然后我就读
gonna skip over to chapter 2 and start
要跳到第2章并开始
with verse 18 and read to the end of the
与第18节一起读到结尾
chapter just so we get a flow of thought
章只是为了让我们得到思想的流动
of here's what God's design is for
这是上帝的设计是为了什么
marriage Genesis 1:26 27 and 28 then God
婚姻创世纪1:26 27和28然后是上帝
said let us make man in our image so
说，我们要照着我们的形象这么
this is day 6 of creation according to
这是根据创作的第6天
our likeness let them rule over the fish
我们的相似让他们统治着鱼
of the sea over
海过的
birds of the sky over the cattle over
牛群上空的鸟儿
all the earth and over every creeping
整个地球和每一个爬行
thing that creeps on the earth God
在地球上爬行的东西上帝
created man in his own image in the
在他自己的形象造人
image of God he created him male and
上帝的形象，他创造了他男性和
female he created them and God blessed
女性他创造了他们，上帝保佑
them and God said to them be fruitful
他们和上帝对他们说是富有成效的
and multiply and fill the earth and
并且繁殖并填充地球和
subdue it and rule over the fish of the
征服它而过的鱼治
sea and over the birds of the sky and
大海和天空的鸟儿
over every living thing that moves on
在每一个继续前进的生物上
the earth and I'll skip over to chapter
地球，我会跳到章节
2 and we'll pick up with verse 18 then
2然后我们将接受第18节
the Lord God said it's not good for the
耶和华神说这是不 利于
man to be alone I will make him a helper
男人独自一人我会帮助他
suitable for him and out of the ground
适合他和离开地面
the Lord God formed every beast of the
耶和华神用地上的每一个野兽
field and every bird of the sky and
田野和 天空中的每一只鸟
brought them to the man to see what he
把他们带到那个男人看他是什么
would call them and whatever the man
会打电话给他们，无论男人
called a living creature that was its
被称为活物，是其
name and the man gave names to all the
名字和男人给了所有的名字
cattle to the birds of the sky to every
牛到天空的鸟儿到每一个
beast of the field but for Adam there
野外的野兽， 但对于亚当那里
was not found a helper suitable for him
没有找到适合他的帮手
so the Lord God caused the deep sleep to
所以耶和华神使深睡眠
fall upon the man and he slept then he
堕落在那个男人身上然后他就睡了
took one of his ribs and closed up the
拿了他的一根肋骨，关上了
flesh at that place and the Lord God
那个地方的肉和主神
fashioned it into a woman the rib which
将它塑造成一个女人的肋骨
he had taken from the man and brought
他从男人身上带走了
her to the man and the man said Wow no
她对男人和男人说哇没有
that's not what it says it's kind of
这不是它所说的那种
what the Hebrew is emphasizing though he
希伯来语虽然强调了什么
says now at last this is now bone of my
现在终于说现在这是我的骨头
bones and flesh of my flesh she shall be
我应该是肉体的骨头和肉体
called woman because she was taken out
叫女人，因为她被带走了
of man for this cause a man shall leave
因此，男人应该离开
his father and mother and shall cleave
他的父亲和母亲将会劈开
to his wife and shall become one flesh
他的妻子，将成为一个肉体
and the man and his wife were both naked
那男人和他的妻子都赤身裸体
and were not ashamed do you agree with
你是否同意并不感到羞耻？
me that those are crucial for our
我认为那些对我们来说至关重要
culture right now they're giving us
他们现在正在给我们文化
God's blueprint for marriage purpose
上帝的婚姻蓝图
number one companionship look at chapter
头号陪伴看看章
2 verse 18 this is so encouraging and
2第18节，这是如此鼓舞人心的，并
then I have a caution for you as we go
我们走的时候会对你保持警惕
through each one of these sees the Lord
通过对这些每一个 看到主
God said it's not good for the man to be
上帝说这不是 好男人是
alone let's talk about that phrase not
让我们谈论这句话不是
good for a moment go back to chapter 1
好一会儿回到第1章
and look at verse 10 this is the first
看看第10节这是第一个
time in the creation week that God has
上帝创造周的时间
said that something's not good
说有些事不好
and ladies what I'm about to say ought
和女士们我要说的应该是什么
to really encourage you here on a
真的鼓励你在这里
Saturday morning so God says it's good
星期六早上所以上帝说这很好
it's good chapter 1 verse 10 says and
第1节第10节说的很好
God called the dry land earth and
上帝称干土为地球
gathered of the waters he called seas
聚集了他称之为海洋的水域
and God saw that it was good throughout
上帝看到它一切都好
the the creation week God says it was
上帝所说的创造周
good it was good it was good it was good
很好，它很好很好
and don't think of Genesis 1 and 2 as
并且不要将创世纪1和2视为
chronology chapter 1 then chapter 2
年表第1章然后第2章
think of chapter 2 as the expansion of
认为第2章作为扩大
day 6 of creation so here we have on day
创作的第6天，所以我们在这一天
6 of creation God has created man every
神创造了每一个人
other day he said it was good it was
有一天他说这很好
good it was good
这很好
but man's by himself and for the first
但男人是他自己和第一个
time God says it's not good so what made
时间上帝说这不好， 所以是什么造成的
the creation at the end of chapter 1 God
在第一章末尾的创造上帝
says it is verse 31 God saw that he had
说是第31节，上帝看到他有
all that he had made that would be after
所有他所做的就是追随
Eve was made remember chapter 2 is on
夏娃被记得第2章正在进行中
day 6 which is at the end of chapter 1
第6天， 即第1章末尾
God sees everything now that he had made
上帝现在看到了他所做的一切
which includes woman and after woman is
其中包括女人和女人
made and marriage is instituted now God
制造和婚姻现在是上帝
says it's very good ladies does that
说这是非常好的女士那样做
make you feel good this morning so
今天早上让你感觉良好
you're the crowning act of God's
你是上帝的最高行为
creation and then God makes marriage he
创造，然后上帝使他结婚
Institute's marriage and now he says
研究所的婚姻，现在他说
it's very good let's think a little bit
这是非常好的让我们思考一下
more about this and I love the way that
更多关于这一点，我喜欢这样的方式
Jay Adams has the definition that he
杰伊亚当斯有他的定义
used years ago for what is marriage and
几年前用于什么是婚姻和
I'm going to just elaborate on this a
我将详细说明这个问题
little bit that marriage is a covenant
婚姻是契约的一点点
of companionship covenant of
约会的契约
companionship God says here I need it's
陪伴上帝在这里说我需要它
not good for man to be alone I will make
我会做的 不是一个人独处的好处
him a helper suitable for him now I want
他现在是我想要的适合他的帮手
to give you a caution I want to caution
给你一个警告我要谨慎
you not to read
你不读
loneliness into this that's not what the
寂寞进入这个不是什么了
Hebrew text says the Hebrew text says
希伯来文说希伯来文说
it's not here's literally what it says
这不是它的字面意思
it's not good for man to be by himself I
我自己独处并不好
have a written you can think about the
有一个书面你可以想想
implications of this I have a really
这个含义我真的有
hard time seeing loneliness before the
很难看到之前的寂寞
fall
秋季
loneliness sounds to me like something
寂寞听起来像是什么东西
that would happen because of Genesis 3
这会发生，因为创世纪3
and sin and I have a really hard time
和罪恶，我真的很难过
reading emptiness neediness in Chapter
阅读章节中的空虚需要
two
二
when the fall hasn't even happened so
当堕落甚至没有发生时
were made for relationship listen
是为了关系倾听
carefully to what I'm about to say we're
小心翼翼地说我要说的就是我们
made for relationship but sin has
为关系而做，但罪有
distorted this and turned it into
扭曲了这一点并把它变成了
neediness Adam was made to give to Eve
亚当被要求给夏娃
Eve was made to give to Adam they both
夏娃被要求给他们两个人
were made for perfect relationship with
与...完美的关系
God but it was void of neediness in
上帝，但它是neediness的虚空中
Chapter two
第二章
you can't have neediness before the fall
在秋天之前你不能有需要
that is a result of sin and the sins
这是罪和罪的结果
curse on the world emptiness and I need
诅咒世界空虚，我需要
you to be certain things for me and you
你要为我和你确定一些事情
can just think about the implications of
可以只考虑一下它的含义
that
那
now let's elaborate on the idea of
现在让我们详细说明一下这个想法
companionship and where am I getting the
陪伴，我在哪里得到
word companion from turn with me to
与我同行的词伴侣
proverbs chapter 2 and when describing
谚语第2章和描述时
marriage the Old Testament in both
在旧约中结婚
proverbs 2 and we won't take the time to
谚语2，我们不会花时间
go to this other passage but Malachi
去其他段落，但玛拉基
2:14 so proverbs 2:17 and Malachi 2:14
2:14所以箴言2:17和玛拉基书2:14
both use the word companion when
两者都使用伴侣这个词
describing marriage so proverbs chapter
描述婚姻如此谚语章节
2 and why is God against adultery listen
2为什么上帝反对通奸倾听
to proverbs chapter 2 and what God says
箴言第2章和上帝所说的
about the woman who breaks her marriage
关于打破婚姻的女人
covenant proverbs 217 I'll start with
圣约箴言217我将开始
verse 16 to give you a little bit of a
16节给你 的 一点点
flow to deliver you from the strange
流动， 让你从奇怪的
woman from the adulteress who flatters
奉承的女人
with her words that leaves the companion
用她离开同伴的话
of her youth
她的青春
and forgets the covenant of our gods so
并忘记了我们神的约
there we have that idea of what is
我们有什么想法
marriage marriage biblically is a
婚姻婚姻圣经是一种
covenant of companionship the word
约会的契约这个词
companion both here and in Malachi 2:14
在这里和玛拉基书中的同伴2:14
is none other than just the Hebrew word
不仅仅是希伯来语
for friends this person is your most
对于朋友来说， 这个人是你最好的
intimate close friend your companion so
亲密的亲密朋友你的同伴如此
a question and as I go through each one
一个问题，当我经历每个问题
of these sees I'm going to pose some
这些看到我会构成一些
questions for us that we could ask young
问题对我们来说，我们可以问年轻
people is this person would this person
人是这个人会是这个人
be your friend is this person primarily
成为你的朋友主要是这个人
your friend as you're thinking about is
你正在考虑的是你的朋友
this a person I could marry well is this
这个我可以嫁得好的人就是这个
person your friend well why is that
人你的朋友为什么这样
important because that's not how a lot
很重要， 因为那不是很多
of relationships are started right now a
关系现在就开始了
lot of relationships are just based upon
很多关系只是基于
the sexual it's based upon physical
性是基于身体的
attraction and it's not about are we
吸引力， 它不是关于我们
friends am I committed to this person as
朋友， 我是这样对待这个人的
a friend it's I like this person's body
朋友，我喜欢这个人的身体
I like the way this person makes me feel
我喜欢这个人让我感受到的方式
so a basic question would be is this
所以一个基本问题就是这个
person my friend marriage is about a
我朋友的婚姻是关于一个人的
covenant of companionship one last
最后的陪伴之约
comment on this one before we move on to
在我们继续之前评论这个
the next C completer
下一个C完成者
and make sure you write in so you can
并确保你写信所以你可以
look at it another time
再看看它
Malachi 2:14 uses the same word for
玛拉基书2:14使用同一个词
companion and uses the word covenant
伴侣并使用契约这个词
about the the men of Judah who were
关于那些犹大人
abandoning their wives and why God was
放弃他们的妻子以及为什么是上帝
so upset with them it's because they
他们很生气，因为他们
were breaking the covenant with their
与他们的约会打破了约
companion that they had made one last
他们最后做的一个伴侣
comment on the two great Commandments
评论两条伟大的诫命
please think about the two great
请想想这两个伟大的
Commandments this way and this is all
诫命这样，这就是全部
tied into that whole idea of how do we
与我们的整体想法联系在一起
think about what is the role of another
想想另一个人的角色是什么
human in my life it cannot be the two
人生在我的生命中不可能是两个
great Commandments our love the Lord
伟大的诫命我们爱主
your God with all your heart soul mind
你的神与你所有的心脏灵魂心灵
and strength and love your neighbor as
和力量， 爱你的邻居
yourself
你自己
so I'll just summarize it into loving
所以我只是把它归结为爱
God loving others it cannot be loving
上帝爱别人，不能爱
God loving others it can't be that way
上帝爱别人，不可能那样
it just it won't work it has to be
只是它不会工作它必须是
loving God loving others biblically if I
如果我爱上帝，就会爱上圣经
have anything else on the same level as
还有其他任何与...相同的水平
relationship with the Lord what do I
与主的关系我是什么
have in my life
在我的生命中
that's idolatry I can't have anything
这是偶像崇拜， 我什么都没有
else at the same level God has to be the
否则在同一水平上帝必须是
rock even if the other person is a rock
摇滚即使对方是摇滚乐
in my life loving God loving others
在我的生命中，爱上帝爱别人
let's move on to the second see a
让我们继续看第二个看到的
completer boy is this controversial
完全男孩是这个有争议的
Genesis 2 back to Genesis 2:18 boy this
创世纪2回到创世纪2:18这个男孩
this is controversial in our culture
这在我们的文化中是有争议的
right now then the Lord God said it's
现在，主上帝说它是
not good for the man to be alone last
这个男人最后独自一人并不好
phrase I will make him a helper suitable
这句话我会让他成为一个 合适 的帮手
for him helper suitable for him let's
对他而言适合他的助手让我们
talk about this controversial phrase and
谈论这个有争议的短语和
what this helper suitable for him here's
这个助手在这里适合他的是什么
a couple of words for you to write down
几句话让你写下来
for further study and then I want to
进一步研究然后我想
make a recommendation of a book in the
提出一本书的推荐
biblical counseling movement we are
圣经咨询运动我们是
complementarian in our view of husband
我们对丈夫的看法是互补的
and wife roles not egalitarian and if
和妻子的角色不是平等的， 如果
that doesn't make sense to you here's
这对你没有意义
some recommended reading for you to do
一些推荐阅读给你做
some further research that this is a big
进一步研究表明这是一个很大的问题
issue in even in the evangelical church
甚至在福音派教会中的问题
egalitarianism versus complementarianism
平等主义与互补主义
John Piper and Wayne Grudem have written
John Piper和Wayne Grudem写过
a wonderful book for us to use called
一本精彩的书供我们使用
recovering biblical manhood and
恢复圣经的男子气概
womanhood I've used mine so much that
女人我很好地使用了我的
it's falling apart it's a great
它正在崩溃， 这是一个伟大的
reference book it's about this thick
参考书就是这么厚
it's not the kind of book you just sit
这不是你刚坐 的那种书
down and just read it's a book that you
下来， 刚读这是一本书，你
use as a reference book to think about
用作思考的参考书
men and women's roles and all the
男人和女人的角色和所有
controversial issues recovering biblical
有争议的问题正在恢复圣经
manhood and womanhood let's think a
男人和女人， 让我们想一个
little bit more about this this idea of
多一点关于这个这个想法
a completer the amplified says this
放大的完成者说这个
you're not familiar with the amplified
你不熟悉放大的
I'd urge you to get familiar with the
我恳请你熟悉一下
amplified translations that
放大翻译
translation it's one of my favorite and
翻译它是我最喜欢的和
the amplified translates this phrase
放大翻译这句话
helper meet and then as is the case with
帮助者见面，然后就是这样
the amplified expands it in parentheses
放大后将它扩展到括号中
and says helper me helper suitable
并说帮助我帮助合适
helper adapted to helper completing
助手适应帮助完成
let's think about it a little bit more
让我们想想这多一点点
and I'm gonna give you a breakdown of
而且我会给你一个故障
what the two Hebrew words mean help meet
两个希伯来语的意思是帮助满足
or helper suitable here's the word
或帮助适合这里的话
helper it is an ally it's often a
帮助它是一个盟友，它经常是一个
military term in the Old Testament and
旧约和旧约中的军事术语
Ally it's the assistant
Ally是助手
it's the aide someone who's coming to
它是助手的人谁的来
the assistance of someone else the aide
助手的帮助
the assistant now ladies you're really
现在助理的女士你真的
gonna love this especially as you relate
要特别喜欢你，这会特别喜欢这个
to your husband and I just freely admit
对你的丈夫和我只是自由地承认
this is what my wife needs to be in my
这是我的妻子需要在我的
life here's what I read in one
生活在这里是我在一个人看到的
commentary of a description of this
评论对此的描述
Hebrew word aide or helper as one
希伯来文的助手或辅助作为一个
suckers the miserable and destitute I
吸吮我的悲惨和贫困
need that my wife needs to do that with
需要我的妻子需要这样做
me as one comforts the miserable and
我是一个安慰悲惨的人
destitute often is referring to the
贫困经常指的是
assistant the comforter the aide the
帮助安慰者的助手
helper and then the the word suitable is
帮助者，然后适当的词是
the helper that is corresponding to the
这是对应于 辅助
helper corresponding to it's the same
对应它的助手是一样的
phrase that's used in verse 20 just a
在第20节中使用的短语只是一个
few verses later maybe you remember the
几节后，也许你还记得
hymn come thou fount and we sing here I
赞美诗来了，我们在这里唱歌
raise my Ebenezer that is the same
提高我的Ebenezer 是一样的
Hebrew word nazar a stone of help I'm
希伯来语纳扎尔是一块帮助我的石头
raising a memorial to remember the times
举起纪念馆来纪念时代
in my life here I raise my Ebenezer I'm
在我的生活中，我抚养我的Ebenezer
building a memorial to the memory of all
建立纪念所有人的纪念碑
the times that God has helped me in my
上帝帮助我的时代
life I'm going to build a monument in
生活我要打造一座纪念碑
Ebenezer a stone of help the completer
Ebenezer 帮助完成者的石头
we believe
我们相信
complementary roles not like dinner
互补的角色不像晚餐
halls at the restaurant complementary
餐厅的大厅互补
roles but complementary as in we
角色， 但我们互补
complement one another and let's just
相互补充，让我们公正
pause for a moment and just think about
暂停片刻，想一想
this this idea of complementary roles
这个互补角色的想法
because it is so controversial even in
因为它甚至在如此具有争议性
the evangelical church what we mean by
福音派教会我们的意思
complementary roles a little bit later
稍后补充角色
today we're gonna Wayne will be speaking
今天我们要去韦恩说话
on the role of the wife and I'll be
关于妻子的角色，我会
speaking on the role the husband and
谈到对角色的丈夫和
this topic will come up again later on
这个话题将在稍后再次 提出
today but I have an illustration with me
今天， 但我有一个插图与我
just to think about complementary roles
只是想想互补的角色
and the part of the country where I come
和我来的国家的一部分
from you're not a real man unless you
除非你，否则你不是真正的男人
carry a pocketknife so I have my
随身携带小折刀，所以我有我的
pocketknife with me today and I won't go
今天和我一起折刀，我不会去
into details about what these blades are
详细了解这些刀片是什么
used for but I'm a hunter so you can use
用于，但我是一个猎人，所以你可以使用
your imagination alright and for the
你的想象力还好
purpose of my illustration I don't know
我的插图的目的我不知道
if you can see that but the blades are
如果你能看到，但刀片是
different on this knife they're
他们是这把刀的不同之处
different by design they're designed to
不同的设计他们的设计
fulfill different roles and you would
履行不同的角色，你会的
never be able to get me to decide which
永远无法让我决定哪个
blade is more important than the other
刀片比另一个更重要
blade depends on what I'm using my knife
刀片取决于我用的是什么刀
for so well I'll just tell you since I'm
好吧，我会告诉你，因为我
a hunter this is the gutting blade this
一个猎人这是这个去内脏的刀片
is the skinning blade and my wife very
是剥皮刀和我的妻子很
wisely asked me when she wants to borrow
明智地问我什么时候想要借钱
my knife if we're on a picnic or
我的刀，如果我们正在野餐或
something she says what was the last
她说的是最后一件事
thing your knife was used for that's a
你的刀被用来做的事情是
very smart question to ask I do
问我很聪明的问题
disinfect the blades from time to time
不时对刀片进行消毒
one blade is not more important than the
一个刀片并不比它重要
other blade they're different by design
其他刀片他们的设计不同
it's this whole issue about men and
这是关于男人和男人的整个问题
women's roles is not about inferiority
女性的角色不是自卑
and superiority that's not the issue
而优势不是问题
it's what were we designed by God to
这是我们为上帝设计的
fulfill on the planet so completer
在地球上实现如此完美
companion completer let's go to the next
同伴完成让我们去下一个
one which is absolutely crucial it's a
一个绝对至关重要的是它
covenant
盟约
relationship covenant relationship and
关系契约关系和
you wonder okay where are you getting
你好不好，你在哪里得到
covenant because covenant is not in this
契约，因为契约不在此
text look at verse 23 and this is where
文字看第23节，这是在哪里
I get the idea of covenant anytime flesh
我得到 约随时随地肉体 的想法
is cut in the Old Testament my brain
在旧约圣经中被切断了
starts to think covenant so verse 23
开始思考圣约23节
this is now bone of my bones flesh of my
这是我骨子里的骨头
flesh she shall be called woman because
肉体，她将被称为女人，因为
she was taken out of man well we also
我们也很好地被带走了
know from Ephesians 5 right that this is
从以弗所书5章知道这是正确的
picturing Christ's relationship with the
描绘基督与圣徒的关系
church let me give you a crucial bit of
教会让我给你一个关键的一点
thinking about this whole idea of
思考这整个想法
covenant relationship when it comes to
当谈到立约的关系
marriage God did not say I'm gonna
婚姻上帝没有说我会
create marriage and then as an
创造婚姻，然后作为一个
afterthought he said oh yeah that is a
事后他说，哦，是的，这是一个
really good picture of Christ's
基督的很棒的照片
relationship in the church that's not
教会中的关系不是
the way it worked I really appreciate
它的工作方式我真的很感激
what John Piper the John Piper pointed
什么约翰·派的约翰·派博指出
this out many years ago in reading that
许多年前在读这个
I was reading about marriage and I
我正在读关于婚姻和我
thought thank you that was really
觉得谢谢你真的
helpful Christ was the lamb slain before
有帮助的基督是被杀的羔羊
the foundation of the world and
世界的基础 和
Ephesians says you were elect in him
以弗所书说你被选中了
before the foundation of the world you
在世界建立之前 你
were chosen in him so his idea of Christ
在他身上选择了他对基督的看法
in the church was before this all
在教堂里面就是这一切
started and he purposely created
他开始故意创造
marriage to be a picture of Christ and
婚姻是基督和
the church not the other way around
教会不是相反的
he created marriage and then as an
他创造了婚姻，然后作为一个
afterthought said oh yeah that's a
事后说，哦，是的，这是一个
really good picture of Christ in the
在基督里真的很好的照片
church now what that ought to do is
教会现在应该做的是
elevate our view of marriage when we are
提升我们对婚姻的看法
married this is picturing something
结婚这是想象的东西
incredibly important incredibly
非常重要的令人难以置信
important it's a covenant relationship
重要的是它是一个契约关系
and you can go to Ephesians 5:22 to 32
你可以去以弗所书5:22到32
and read about that covenant
并阅读有关该契约的内容
relationship but I want to talk a little
关系，但我想谈一点
bit since it is so easy to get divorce
因为它位那么容易得到离婚
divorced in our culture I want to talk a
在我们的文化中离婚我想谈谈
little bit about the idea of the
关于这个想法的一 点点
covenant and what does the Bible mean
圣约和圣经的含义是什么
remember our definition
记住我们的定义
is a covenant of companionship so let's
是一个陪伴的盟约，所以让我们
talk about what does it mean to enter
说说这是什么意思进入
into a covenant with a person and our
与一个人和我们的约
young people maybe all your council
年轻人可能都是你的理事会
leaves but especially our young people
离开，尤其是我们的年轻人
need to get a really good view of this
需要得到这一个很好的 观点
of we're entering into a covenant
我们正在订立一个约
relationship this just isn't a
关系这不是一个
contractual relationship that is easily
契约关系很容易
broken which our culture makes so easy
打破了我们的文化如此轻松
to break Scripture calls it a covenant
打破圣经称它为契约
the word covenant in the Old Testament
旧约中的圣约一词
is the word Bharath big riff and what it
是 Bharath大侦察 这个词 ，它是什么
means is to cut to cut so the phrase in
意思是削减切割所以短语
the Old Testament when a covenant may is
旧约圣约可能是契约
made is to cut a covenant now let me
现在就是切割一个契约让我
show you right in this same book a few
在同一本书中向你展示了一些
chapters later I'd like you to go back
章节后我想让你回去
to Genesis 15 and let me show you a
到创世纪15，让我告诉你一个
covenant being made and then I'm gonna
约会正在制定然后我会
make some applications to marriage
对婚姻提出一些申请
especially the marriage ceremony Genesis
特别是结婚仪式创世纪
chapter 15 this is God cutting a
第15章这是上帝切割的
covenant making a covenant with Abraham
约定与亚伯拉罕立约
and here in Genesis 15 we read this
在创世纪15章，我们读到了这一点
verse 9 I'm gonna read 9 to 12 and then
第9节我要读9到12然后
I'm gonna skip to 17 and 18 so he said
我要跳到17和18，所以他说
to him this is God to Abraham bring me a
对他来说，这是上帝给亚伯拉罕带给我的
three-year-old heifer and a three year
三岁的小母牛和一个三年
old female goat goat in a three year old
在一个三岁 老的母山羊山羊
Ram and a Turtledove and a young pigeon
拉姆和斑鸠和一羽幼鸽
then he brought all these to him and cut
然后他把所有这些都带给了他并切断了
them in two and laid each half opposite
他们分成两半，每半个对立
the other but he did not cut the birds
另一个，但他没有削减鸟类
and the birds of prey came down upon the
那猛禽降下来了
carcasses and Abraham drove them away
尸体和亚伯拉罕把它们赶走了
now when the Sun was going down a deep
现在当太阳下山深处
sleep fell upon Abraham and behold
睡在亚伯拉罕身上，看哪
terror and great darkness fell upon him
恐怖和黑暗笼罩在他身上
skip down if you would a few verses and
如果您想要几节经文，请跳过
I'm gonna read 17 and 18 and it came
我要读17和18， 它来了
about when the Sun had set that it was
关于太阳落山的时候
very dark and behold there appeared a
非常黑暗，看到出现了一个
smoking oven and a flaming torch which
吸烟炉和燃烧的火炬
which passed between these pieces on
这些部件之间传递
that day the Lord made a covenant with
那天，耶和华与他立约
Abraham saying to your descendants I
亚伯拉罕对你的后代说：
given this land from the river of Egypt
这片土地来自埃及河
as far as the Great River the river
至于大河这条河
Euphrates here's what the Covenant I
幼发拉底河这是契约我
mean this is pretty gory scene right can
意味着这是非常血腥的场景吧
you imagine a animal cut in pieces and
你想象一个切成碎片的动物
then God passes between the pieces
然后上帝在碎片之间穿过
here's what God is saying or anytime you
这是上帝在说或任何时候你 说的 话
enter into a covenant with a person and
与某人签订契约
you pass between the pieces may this
你可以在这些作品之间穿过
happened to me there's a phrase in
碰巧在我身上有一句话
Hebrew may this happen to me and more
希伯来语可能会发生在我身上，甚至更多
also if I don't keep my word God is
如果我不守信，上帝就是
saying may I become like these
说我可能会变成这样的
slaughtered animals if I don't uphold my
如果我不坚持我的屠宰动物
end of the bargain
交易结束了
does that heighten your idea of what a
这会增加你对什么的看法
covenant means now I think there's
契约意味着现在我认为有
implications even in this of our
甚至在我们这个方面的影响
traditional marriage ceremony think
传统婚礼认为
about in a traditional marriage ceremony
关于传统的婚礼仪式
you walk into the the church building
你走进教堂
and someone traditionally would say
而传统上会有人说
pieces the sides are you a friend of the
你是双方的朋友
bride you a friend of the groom and what
新娘你是新郎的朋友和什么
happens the bride and her father walk
新娘和她父亲走路时发生了
between the the people that are in
的是在人与人之间
witnessing the ceremony and it's all a
目睹仪式，这一切都是
sacred ceremony before God a covenant is
在上帝圣约之前的神圣仪式
being made in the Old Testament or in
在旧约 或正在取得
Old Testament Middle Eastern culture
旧约中东文化
when a covenant was made there was a
当一个约定出来时，有一个
feast afterwards
之后的盛宴
words and we have a marriage reception
我们有一个婚礼招待会
afterwards we even have remnants of the
之后我们甚至还有残余的
Covenant being made even in our
契约甚至在我们的
traditional marriage ceremony and that's
传统婚礼仪式就是这样
an interesting thing to research is
研究的一个有趣的事情是
where did all of our traditions come
我们所有的传统都来自哪里
from in the marriage ceremony and I
从婚礼仪式和我
think there's implications of the
认为有产生的影响
Covenant so what are some questions and
契约所以有些问题和问题
I skipped over purpose two of the
我跳过了两个目的
completer and I'll just I'll run
完成，我只会跑
together purpose two in purpose three
共同目的两个目的三
what are some questions that we could
我们可以提出什么问题
give to young people to help them in
给年轻人，帮助他们在
their choice of a marriage partner so
他们选择婚姻伴侣这样
purpose to a completer for the man does
目的是为了男人的完成者
this woman compliment me now not
这个女人现在不赞美我
compliment with an i but complement with
赞美我，但补充
another ii
另一个ii
is she a completer to me or for the
是她完成者对我或对
woman asking can I complete this man or
女人问我可以完成这个男人或
another really important question that
另一个非常重要的问题
she should be asking is can I follow his
她应该问我是否可以跟随他
leadership purpose 3 the Covenant am I
领导目的3我是盟约
willing to enter into a covenant with
愿意与之立约
this person that's a really basic
这个人真的很基础
question but a lot of young people need
问题， 但很多年轻人需要
to ask that question am I willing and
问这个问题我 愿意和
I'm gonna give you a definition of a
我要给你一个定义
covenant here in just a moment but am I
我立刻在这里立刻约会但是我
willing to enter into a lifelong
愿意进入终身
commitment with this person am I willing
我愿意和这个人一起做出承诺
to cut a covenant with this person so am
如此与这个人立约
I willing to enter into a lifelong
我愿意进入终身
relationship or for the man am I willing
我愿意和男人的关系
to love this woman as Christ loves the
要像基督所爱的那样爱这个女人
church he fusions 5 or 4 the woman am I
教会他融合5或4女人是我
willing to love this man as the church
愿意爱这个人作为教会
does Christ we have to help people raise
基督我们必须帮助人们提高
their view of marriage a covenant
他们对婚姻的看法是一个契约
relationship here's a definition of a
这里的关系是对a的定义
covenant a serious lifelong commitment
契约是一种严肃的终身承诺
made before God and others to fulfill
在上帝和其他人面前成就
vows remember the animal being cut and
发誓要记住被切割的动物
may this happen to me and more also if I
这可能发生在我身上， 如果我发生的话
do not fulfill my end of the agreement a
不履行协议的终点a
serious lifelong commitment made before
以前认真做出的终身承诺
God and others to fulfill vows
上帝和其他人发誓
a covenant relationship what is marriage
一个契约关系什么是婚姻
a covenant of companionship now you have
现在你有一份陪伴之约
an extra handout at the end of this
在这结束时额外的讲义
section of notes called the Christian
一段称为基督徒的笔记
marriage covenant I'm going to give you
婚约我要给你
a little bit of a history behind this
这背后有一段历史
this comes from a ministry that I'm
这来自我的一个事工
involved with called peacemaker
参与调用的和事佬
ministries and peacemaker ministries is
各部委和和平部委是
so concerned about people understanding
如此关注人们的理解
their marriage commitments that they
他们的婚姻承诺
came up with this for young people to
为年轻人想出了这个
sign ahead of time saying that before we
提前签字说我们之前
get married or when we get married we
结婚或结婚时我们
recognize we're entering into a covenant
认识到我们正在订立一个盟约
that if we ever get to the place where
如果我们到达那里的地方
we're not getting along we will go get
我们不相处我们会得到
counseling so you're agreeing at the
咨询，所以你同意
time of marriage or even ahead of time
结婚的时候，甚至提前
that we are entering into a covenant and
我们正在订立一个契约和
if there are things where we are going
如果有些事情我们要去的地方
we are wanting to divorce one another
我们想要彼此离婚
instead we will go to a biblical
相反， 我们将去圣经
conciliator to try to work out things
调解员试图解决问题
we'll go to a biblical mediator or a
我们会去圣经的调解员或者
biblical conciliator I'm not gonna read
圣经调解人我不会读
that whole thing you can read it just so
整个事情，你可以这样看
you get the flow of thought let me give
你得到了 我给予的思想
you another interesting little tidbit
你另一个有趣的小花絮
some states are passing legislation
一些州正在通过立法
right now because they're so concerned
现在因为他们如此关注
about what's happening to the demise of
关于发生了什么 的灭亡
marriage I wish California was like this
婚姻我希望加州是这样的
but Louisiana passed a law in recent
但路易斯安那最近通过了一项法律
years called the Covenant
多年来被称为盟约
marriage law when you go to get your
当你去获得你的婚姻法
marriage license in Louisiana right now
现在路易斯安那州的结婚证
you can choose two options you can go
你可以选择两个选项，你可以去
get your marriage license and call they
拿到你的结婚证并打电话给他们
jokingly call it regular and high test
开玩笑地称它为常规和高测试
you can go get the regular marriage
你可以去定期结婚
license which is just like every other
许可证就像其他人一样
state which would allow for divorce
允许离婚的国家
easily etc or you can go get the
容易等，或者你可以得到
covenant marriage license where you're
契约婚姻许可你在哪里
stating as a couple young couple before
以前说过几对年轻夫妇
you get married you go get your marriage
你结婚了， 你去结婚吧
license and you sign a document saying
许可证，你签署一份文件说
that if we ever it's very much similar
如果我们它非常相似的话
to this peacemaker many ministries
这个和平缔造者很多部委
document that if we hit problems in our
记录如果我们遇到了问题
marriage and we're wanting to divorce we
结婚，我们想和我们离婚
are committing to each other ahead of
就在前面的承诺彼此
time that we will go get marriage
我们将结婚的时间
counseling
辅导服务
guess which one most young couples are
猜猜哪一对年轻夫妇是谁
signing up for in the state of Louisiana
在 路易斯安那州 报名参加
covenant marriage because most people
圣约婚姻，因为大多数人
are wanting their marriage is to last
希望他们的婚姻能够持久
right covenant covenant so companionship
正义契约如此契约
completer covenant let's move on to the
完成契约让我们继续前进
next one obviously children again this
下一个显然是孩子了
needs to be addressed in our culture
需要在我们的文化中加以解决
because children unfortunately in our
因为孩子不幸在我们这里
culture many people view them as a
文化很多人把它们视为一种
hassle
争论
but chapter one Psalm 127 one says
但第一章诗篇127篇有人说
children are a heritage from the Lord
孩子是 主的遗产
again I have a caution for you here with
再次，我在这里谨慎对待你
chapter 1 verse 28 let me read the image
第1章28节让我读一下这个图像
bearing verses again verse 26 then God
再说第26节然后上帝
said let us make man in our image
说让我们按照我们的形象造人
according to our likeness let them rule
根据我们的相似，让他们统治
over the fish of the sea over the birds
过海 的 过飞鸟 鱼
of the sky over the cattle over all
在所有的牛群上空的天空
crawl the earth over every creeping
每一次爬行都爬上地球
thing that creeps on the earth and God
在地球和上帝身上爬行的东西
created man in his own image in the
在他自己的形象造人
image of God he created him male and
上帝的形象，他创造了他男性和
female he created them and then God
女他创造了他们，然后是上帝
blessed them and God said to them be
祝福他们，上帝对他们说
fruitful and multiply and fill the earth
富饶而繁衍，充满了大地
and subdue it and rule over the fish of
并征服它而过的鱼治
the sea and over the birds of the sky
大海和天空的鸟儿
and over every living thing that moves
以及每一个移动的生物
on the earth first let me comment on the
地球上的 第一个让我 对评论
idea of how does this relate to image
如何这是否涉及到图像的想法
bearing because it flows right out of
轴承，因为它流过右出的
the image bearing and I wish we had more
图像承载，我希望我们有更多
time to really elaborate on what does it
是时候真正详细说明它是什么了
mean to be image bearers but we're made
意味着成为形象承载者，但我们已经成就了
you are made I'm made to be a reflector
你被塑造我是一个反射器
I'm not made to be the main thing you're
我不会成为 你的主要人物
not made to be the main thing we're made
不是我们制作的主要内容
to be reflectors so it helps us get our
成为反射者，这有助于我们得到我们的
purpose on the planet right when we
我们这个星球上的目的
realize I'm not made for life to revolve
意识到我不是为生命而旋转
around me I'm made to be a reflector of
我的周围，我做成的反射器
the one who life revolves around I'm to
生命围绕着我的那个人
be reflecting glory back to God life is
将荣耀反映回上帝的生命是
about worship we talked a little bit
关于崇拜，我们谈了一点
about that last evening so I'm an
关于那个昨晚所以我是一个
image-bearer I am made to be a worshiper
我是一个崇拜者
and I'm made to reflect glory back to
而我却想要回归荣耀
God so what's how do children fit in
上帝，所以孩子们如何适应
with this what's the point the point is
有了这一点，重点是什么
we are bringing into the world and
我们正在进入这个世界
remember it all ties together I believe
记住，我相信所有的联系在一起
with the Great Commission go into all
与大使命进入一切
the world and make disciples my children
世界，让门徒成为我的孩子
are my primary disciples because I am
是我的主要门徒，因为我
passing down to the next generation the
传递到下一代了
baton of what it means to be an
接力棒是什么意思
image-bearer
图像承载
to live as a god-glorifying person to
作为一个神圣的人生活
live as a worshipper of the true and
作为真实和真实的崇拜者生活
living God so why do we have children
活着的上帝，为什么我们有了孩子
it's because I want to they're my chief
这是因为我想他们是我的首领
disciples I want to pass
门徒我想通过
I want to fulfill the Great Commission
我想完成大使命
with my children and teach them how to
和我的孩子一起教他们如何
live a god-glorifying
过着神圣的荣耀
life as an image-bearer now here's a
作为形象持有人的生活现在这里是一个
caution related to this I am a home
与此相关的谨慎我是一个家
schooler so don't throw tomatoes at me
小学生所以不要向我扔西红柿
some people have a really bad attitude
有些人的态度很糟糕
about homeschooling we've we're in our
关于在家上学，我们已经在我们的学校
20th year of homeschooling right now
现在是家庭教育的第20年
having homeschooled six children and I
我和六个孩子一起上过孩子
know the homeschooling movement real
知道家庭学校运动真实
well and I understand that some people
好吧，我理解有些人
interpret these verses as you're not
解释这些经文，因为你不是
spiritual unless you have a large amount
精神，除非你有大量的
of children now let me give you a
孩子现在让我给你一个
caution that's not what verse 28 says
请注意，这不是第28节所说的
it's not a command - you have to drive a
这不是命令- 你必须开车
15-passenger van that is not what verse
15乘客面包车不是什么经文
28 is it is a blessing and God blessed
28这是一种祝福，上帝保佑
them and said may you be fruitful and
他们说，你可能会有成果
multiply it is not if you're really
乘它不是，如果你真的
spiritual you have to have eight
精神上你必须有八个
children you have to have ten children
孩子你必须有十个孩子
god bless them may you be fruitful and
上帝保佑他们，你可能会富有成效
multiply and fill the earth now it
现在繁殖并填充地球
sounds somewhat hypocritical because I
听起来有些虚伪，因为我
have six children and God has really
有六个孩子，上帝真的
blessed us Psalm 127 one children are a
祝福我们诗篇127一个孩子是一个
heritage from the Lord let's go to the
从主遗产，让我们去
next one collaboration for God's glory
下一个为上帝的荣耀而合作
collaboration for God's glory that
为了上帝的荣耀而合作
here's an easier way to put it coal
这是一种更简单的煤炭方式
Abers for the Lord that's not quite as
对于主的掠夺者并不如此
much of a mouthful collaboration for
非常慷慨的合作
God's glory again I would build off the
再次荣耀上帝，我会建立起来
idea of image bearing that a man and a
像承载一个男人和一个理念
woman come together and their thinking
女人走到一起，他们的想法
is how can we serve the lord better
我们怎样才能更好地为主服务呢？
together than we could apart and that's
我们在一起比我们可以分开那样
the question that I would have young
我将有年轻人 的问题
people or that I would pose for young
人或我会为年轻人摆姿势
people to ask is can I see myself
人们要问的是我能看到自己吗？
serving the Lord better with this person
这个人更好地事奉主
than I would without this person or
比没有这个人或我没有
another sub question to that to pose for
要构成的另一个子问题
young people would be does this person
年轻人会做这个人
pull me down spiritually or does this /
在灵性上拉我或者这样做/
build me up spiritually collaboration
建立我的精神合作
for God's glory we're building a new
为了上帝的荣耀， 我们正在建立一个新的
team are we better together than we are
团队比我们更好
apart we complement each other with our
除此之外， 我们与我们相互补充
giftedness collaboration for God's glory
为了上帝的荣耀，天赋合作
remember first Corinthians 10:31 again
再次记得哥林多前书10:31
whether we eat or drink or whatever we
无论我们是吃喝还是喝酒
do and that includes marriage we do all
这包括婚姻我们做的一切
to the glory of God and then the last
为了上帝的荣耀，然后是最后的荣耀
purpose close intimate relationship look
目的紧密亲密的关系看
at verses 24 and 25 of chapter 2 and
在节24和第2章的 25和
then a couple of comments and then I'm
那么几个评论，然后我
gonna wrap it up with flying through the
飞起来穿过它
pages on how does this all come together
关于这一切是如何结合在一起的页面
in a marriage relationship for this
在婚姻关系中
cause a man leaves father and mother
导致男人离开父亲和母亲
Cleaves to his wife and they become one
劈开他的妻子，他们成为一体
flesh and the man and his wife were both
肉体和男人和他的妻子都是
naked and were not ashamed the very last
赤身裸体并且最后没有感到羞耻
session today and it's probably good
今天的会议，这可能是好的
that it's the last session because
这是最后一次会议，因为
everybody will be tired but it's about
每个人都会感到厌倦，但这是关于
sexuality so at least everybody will be
所以至少每个人都会有性欲
tuned in even though you're tired during
即使你累了 ，也要收听
the last session so I'm not gonna make a
最后一次会议，所以我不会做一个
lot of comments on that right now but
现在很多评论，但是
one comment to just kind of pave the way
一个评论只是为了铺平道路
for that last session in our culture
我们文化中的最后一次会议
we've put sex at the beginning of the
我们把性生活放在了初期
intimacy chain the way we like to say it
亲密关系链我们喜欢说的方式
in biblical counseling is sex is at the
在圣经辅导中，性是在
end of the intimacy chain God did not
亲密链上帝没有结束
primarily make marriage about sex
主要是关于性的婚姻
that's what our culture says sex is the
这就是我们的文化所说的性
fruit the sexual relationship is the
果实的性关系是
fruit of an intimate relationship more
亲密关系的果实更多
about that during the last session what
关于那个在上一届会议期间的内容
I want to comment on here is the leaving
我想评论这里是离开
and cleaving and then the rest of the
和劈开，然后其余的
notes is about weaving leaving cleaving
笔记是关于编织离开劈开
and weaving is the way we like to think
和编织是我们喜欢思考的方式
about it leave is a really strong word
关于它离开是一个非常强大的词
and there's so many issues related to
并且有很多与之相关的问题
this in our culture right now parents
这在我们的文化，现在的父母
having a hard time letting their kids
很难让他们的孩子
grow up and being controlling and not
长大，控制而不是
letting them grow into adults or
让他们成长为成年人或
children that are overly dependent
过度依赖的孩子
learning leave and cleave issues are
学习假和解决问题
huge right now learning to leave and
现在很大的学习离开和
then cleave the word leave actually
然后实际上切掉这个词
means abandon or forsake it's a really
意味着放弃或抛弃真的
strong word and then the word cleave is
强词然后切割这个词就是
the word for glue you wonder why divorce
胶水这个词你想知道离婚的原因
is so painful well God says you were
上帝说你是如此痛苦
glued together with another person and
与另一个人粘在一起
every so often I do woodworking and if I
我经常做木工，如果我
would try to take a piece of wood apart
会试着把一块木头分开
that I've glued together it doesn't
我把它粘在一起它没有
split where I put the glue it splits in
我把它分开的胶水分开了
the grain and that's what's happening in
谷物，这就是发生的事情
divorce there's an incredible amount of
离婚有数量惊人的
pain that goes on because some gluing
因为有些粘合而继续疼痛
bonding took place leave cleave and then
粘接发生离开，然后
weave a close intimate relationship more
更亲密地建立亲密关系
on that intimacy during the last session
在上届会议期间的那种亲密关系
today let me take just a minute to talk
今天让我花一点时间谈谈
about G and G is all about weaving the
关于G和G是关于编织的
relationship leaving cleaving and
关系离开劈开和
weaving and there's all kinds of ideas
编织，各种各样的想法
here for how to weave a relationship
这里是如何编织关系
together
一起
let me summarize it by using some words
让我用一些词汇总结一下
here's what we need to be thinking about
这是我们需要思考的问题
with marriage and what we're teaching
与婚姻和我们正在教的东西
our Council eaves or when we're doing
我们的委员会屋檐或我们正在做的事情
premarital counseling when it comes to
婚前咨询
helping young people get ready for
帮助年轻人做好准备
marriage you're learning to bond
婚姻你正在学习结合
together with another person marriage is
和另一个人一起结婚
about bonding marriage is about becoming
关于结合婚姻是关于成为
a teammate with a person for life I am
我是一个有生命的人的队友
choosing my teammate for life
选择我的队友终身
now I don't know if any of you read
现在我不知道如果你们读
Western fiction but one of my favorite
西方小说，但我最喜欢的一个
writers is Louis L'Amour and Louis
作家是Louis L'Amour和Louis
L'Amour has this little expression and
倾慕有这个小表情和
that is that person is someone you can
那个人就是你能做的人
ride the river with it's someone you can
用它来骑河是你能做到的
count on well that's what you're looking
指望你正在寻找的东西
for in your partner this is my team mate
对于你的伴侣，这是我的队友
for life
终身
I'm I'm I'm choosing a person that I can
我就是我，我正在选择一个我能做到的人
ride the river with
骑河
bonding teammates and blending leaving
结合队友和混合离开
cleaving and then weaving together God
劈开然后把上帝编织在一起
has blessed me with over 30 years of
祝福我超过30年
marriage now and six children I love my
现在结婚，还有六个孩子，我爱我
wife dearly she truly is my best friend
妻子亲爱的，她真的是我最好的朋友
it didn't start off that way and the way
它并没有从那种方式和方式开始
I tell the young people in our marriage
我告诉年轻人我们的婚姻
and family class at masters is you don't
和大师的家庭班是你没有
find your soul mate you become soul
找到你的灵魂伴侣，你就成了灵魂
mates through years and years of leaving
通过多年和多年的离开
cleaving and weaving of bonding and
切割和编织粘接和
blending lives together working through
混合居住通过共同努力
issues together you find yourself
你发现自己的问题
getting closer and closer and closer and
越来越接近和密切，
that leads to true intimacy and the
导致真正的亲密关系和
fruit of that is a good sexual
这是一个很好的性的果实
relationship and that's what we'll talk
关系，这就是我们要说的
about in the last session today
关于今天的最后一次会议
so in conclusion let me say it's not
所以最后让我说它不是
that God's cruel because he designed
因为他的设计，上帝的残忍
marriage I think his plan is absolutely
婚姻我认为他的计划绝对是
wonderful and if you follow God's
太棒了，如果你跟着上帝的话
blueprint God's ways work we need to
蓝图上帝的方式我们需要的工作
rebuild a marriage culture there's a lot
重建婚姻文化有很多
of negative press right now about
现在关于负面新闻
marriage let's go out and model marriage
婚姻让我们出去塑造婚姻
to the glory of God
为了上帝的荣耀
you
您